Guide to the Palestinian Oral History Project, 2017-2019 RL.11850
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Palestinian Oral History Project
2017-2019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies
Kalow, Nancy
RL.11850
9.5 Gigabytes
234 Files
Oral history interviews with Palestinian students and artists, created by Duke students for the course AMES 204FS, "Documenting the Middle East," taught by Nancy Kalow.
Arrangement
Arrangement is chronological by class year and then alphabetical by interviewee name.
Biographical / Historical
The Palestinian Oral History Project collection was created by classes taught by Nancy Kalow, a Lecturing Fellow at Duke University and instructor at the Center for Documentary Studies. The collection is closely tied to two other collections created through projects and classes directed by Kalow: the Refugee Lives Oral History Project and the Palestinian Student Films.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Palestinian Oral History Project collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2020.
Related Materials
Refugee Lives Oral History Project
Palestinian Student Films
Collection Overview
Twelve oral history interviews with students and artists from Palestine and the Palestinian diaspora, created by classes led by instructor Nancy Kalow between 2017 and 2019. For each interview, students in the class created notes and transcripts, as well as 4-minute audio projects distilled from the interviews, for a Duke Service-Learning website, "Arabic Communities:" https://sites.duke.edu/arabiccommunities/palestine/. The interviewees shared stories of their daily lives, cultural traditions, Palestinian identity, experiences living in refugee camps, their educational experiences, family stories, observations and stories about living under occupation, and their personal and professional interests and activities.
Audiovisual materials; Oral history interviews; Human Rights -- Palestine; Palestine -- Social conditions; Refugee camps -- Palestine; Arab-Israeli conflict
- Interviews, 2017
  Scope and Contents
  Five Duke students in AMES 204FS "Documenting the Middle East" undertook semester-long audio interviewing projects to collect the oral histories of five Palestinians: three in the West Bank, one from Gaza currently residing in Chapel Hill, and one from the Diaspora. Four students recorded two long-form interviews with their interviewees; one student recorded one long-form interview. Interviews were conducted by Skype or in person. Each interview is transcribed, and each student wrote fieldnotes after recording the interviews. The interviewees shared stories of their daily lives, cultural traditions, experiences living in refugee camps, experience as a member of the Palestinian Diaspora, their educational experiences, family stories, observations and stories about living under occupation, and their professional interests and activities. They spoke about Palestinian identity and personal goals. Also included are edited audio projects, four minutes each, which were produced for a Duke Service-Learning website, "Arabic Communities:" https://sites.duke.edu/arabiccommunities/palestine/.
  - AlRob, Sarah, 2017 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0001, E-folder AlRob, Sarah)
    Sarah AlRob is a journalist and filmmaker from Jenin in the West Bank.
  - Eid, Mohammed, 2017 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0001, E-folder Eid, Mohammed)
    Mohammed Eid, from the Gaza Strip, was a Rotary Peace Fellow at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill at the time of his interviews.
  - Jawabreh, Asma, 2017 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0001, E-folder Jawabreh, Asma)
    Asma Jawabreh is a journalist and filmmaker from a refugee camp near Hebron in the West Bank.
  - SD, 2017 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0001, E-folder SD)
    SD is a descendent of Palestinians now residing in the United States.
  - Wahsh, Tasnim, 2017 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0001, E-folder Wahsh, Tasnim)
    Tasnim Wahsh studied media at Hebron University and resides in Hebron in the West Bank.
- Interviews, 2018
  Duke students in AMES 204FS "Documenting the Middle East" undertook semester-long audio interviewing projects to collect the oral histories of four Palestinians: three in the West Bank and one from the Diaspora. Working in pairs, the students recorded two long-form interviews with their interviewees. Interviews were conducted by Skype or in person. Each interview is transcribed, and each student wrote fieldnotes after both interviews. The interviewees shared stories of their daily lives, cultural traditions, experiences living in refugee camps, their educational experiences, family stories, observations and stories about living under occupation, and their professional interests and activities. They spoke about Palestinian identity and personal goals. Also included are edited audio projects, four minutes each, which were produced for a Duke Service-Learning website, "Arabic Communities:" https://sites.duke.edu/arabiccommunities/palestine/.
  - Alatar, Mohammed, 2018 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0002, E-folder Alatar, Mohammed)
    Mohammed Alatar is a filmmaker in Ramallah.
  - Alazza, Mohammed, 2018 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0002, E-folder Alazza, Mohammed)
    Mohammad Alazza is a filmmaker in Bethlehem.
  - Farah, Sofia, 2018 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0002, E-folder Farah, Sofia)
    Sofia Farah is a graduate student at UNC from Chile.
  - Zeitawi, Tala, 2018 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0002, E-folder Zeitawi, Tala)
    Tala Zeitawi is a filmmaker in Ramallah.
- Interviews, 2019
  Duke students in AMES 204FS "Documenting the Middle East" undertook semester-long audio interviewing projects to collect the oral histories of three Palestinians in the West Bank. Students, working in pairs or a group of three, recorded two long-form interviews with their interviewees. Interviews were conducted by Skype. Each interview is transcribed, and each student wrote fieldnotes after recording the interviews. The interviewees shared stories of their daily lives, cultural traditions, experiences living in refugee camps, their educational experiences, family stories, observations and stories about living under occupation, and their professional interests and activities. They spoke about Palestinian identity and personal goals. Also included are edited audio projects, four minutes each, which were produced for a Duke Service-Learning website, "Arabic Communities:" https://sites.duke.edu/arabiccommunities/palestine/.
  - Abushusheh, Sarah, 2019 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0003, E-folder Abushusheh, Sarah)
    Sarah Abushusheh is a filmmaker in Jericho in the West Bank.
  - Al-Bazz, Ahmad, 2019 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0003, E-folder Al-Bazz, Ahmad)
    Ahmad Al-Bazz is a filmmaker and photographer in Nablus in the West Bank.
  - Al-Azzah, Thaer, 2019 (Digital-materials RL11850-SET-0003, E-folder Al-Azzah, Thaer)
    Thaer Al-Azzah is a filmmaker in Bethlehem in the West Bank.